<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/rss.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
    <title>rose / bellatrix</title>
    <link>https://roseis.gay/feed.xml</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>rose / bellatrix &#xa9; 2025</copyright>
    <description>rss feed for roseis.gay</description>
    
    <item>
        <title>new hot chocolate rating (CUP+LID)</title>
        <description>CUP+LID now in the tierlist!! very high scoring, makes me think i need to rearrage things.
&lt;p&gt;white hot chocolate ('25-07): actually very nice, thicker licer texture, all over very good. (B+)
&lt;p&gt;original: sweet, chocolatly, thick, with a little bit of nuttyness. perfect in every way, no compromises, stands out whilst being good at everything (S)
&lt;p&gt;classic white: similar to the Stage white hot chocolate, but more intense with a worse texture, and a weird note I can't quite place. (A+)
&lt;p&gt;ruby: intense, berry-y, nice but too much all at once (A-)
&lt;p&gt;golden toffee: just takes like toffee, great, but barely a hot chocolate (B+)
</description>
        <link>projects/hot-choc</link>
        <pubDate>20 Sep 2025 20:30:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>new hot chocolate rating</title>
        <description>i had my last nectar voucher for a Nero drink, so i've rated their white hot chocolate as a B+.
&lt;p&gt;white hot chocolate ('25-07): actually very nice, thicker licer texture, all over very good. (B+)
</description>
        <link>projects/hot-choc</link>
        <pubDate>17 Jul 2025 20:30:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>west yorkshire metro speedrun record set!!!!</title>
        <description>after three attempts, i've finally managed to complete my Metro speedrun!

&lt;p&gt;on July 15th 2025 i made another attempt of the speedrun, which became my first successful attempt at <b>16h 32m</b>.

&lt;p&gt;i started with the line up to Walsden, before doing the line up to Marsden. i then did the penistone line (including going outside of West Yorkshire to enable me to efficiently get between Denby Dale and Darton). after which i managed to complete the Pontefract Baghill line (ticking off many lines on the way) before completing the Airedale and Wharfedale lines. after this i just had the Horsforth and Micklefield lines, as well as the Dewsbury line up to Ravensthorpe in addition to three left out stations (Streethouse, Featherstone, and Normanton).

&lt;p&gt;at the end to avoid a replacement bus back from Micklefield i continued to Selby and got a TP service back home. unfortunabtly i was not able to use the Grand Central Bradford service at all in this run which would have been fun, but i did manage to get an LNER service between Horsforth and Wakefield Westgate.

&lt;p&gt;this was done on a weekday with a weekly M-Card zones 1-5 pass (the student/u26 one), as well as a few extra tickets (Denby Dale to Darton via Barnsley, as well as the tickets between Micklefield and Selby and then back home).

&lt;p&gt;i had very good luck the entire day, with so significant delays and zero cancellations. i think my starting train was a good decision, and i made some well thought out last minute journey decisions that increased my efficiency a lot. honestly i don't think i can do much better than this, but i'll have another go at some point.
</description>
        <link>projects/wymetro</link>
        <pubDate>17 Jul 2025 00:11:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>bradford: 9th platfrom zero</title>
        <description>2025-07-14

&lt;p&gt;this is slightly embarrassing but i forgot about this one. it opened this year and i remember not being able to attend the opening, and after that just... forget. that's fine now because i have finally done it. with a quick hop over to BDQ (on a lovely LNER (GR) Azuma) i got the train back to LDS from the platform.

&lt;p&gt;the platform zero at BDQ serves a variety of NT services to LDS, ILK, and SKI. apparently there is also an early morning service to LAN as well.
</description>
        <link>/projects/plat0</link>
        <pubDate>14 Jul 2025 20:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>class 701, hot chocolate, and more</title>
        <description>i've been trying to get on a BR class 701 for months now. every time i were i London i would be checking RealTimeTrains constantly to see if there was one operating at that time, but never managed to. until today! I was in London for a Los Campesinos! concert and decided to spend the day running up to the event with a day Travelcard. this time i didn't even check RTT i just happened to arrive in waterloo and it was there.

&lt;p&gt;(i don't know why it's sideways, webp conversion things i guess i'll try fix it at some point no guarantees)

&lt;p&gt;the interior is nice and spacious, with the feel of a TfL Overground BR Class 710 combined with a TL BR Class 700. It has nice information displays everywhere though i feel like they are very underutilised. the Elizabeth line makes excellent use of their displays with onwards connections and different stations, and many National Rail trains now show the next stations departure board on the display, as well as calling times of the coming stations. these trains do not implement this in a good way. often the features are missing, and with TfL connections, they seem to only be shown when the train is already pulling into the station. that being said they are generally pretty good, with that moden Aventra feel. a shame they've had so many problems coming into service, but i'm excited to see more of them.;w
</description>
        <link>/train/BR701</link>
        <pubDate>14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>northumberland line visit!</title>
        <description>on December 15th 2024, the date of the National Rail timetable change, i visited newcastle to go ride the newly restored and reopened Northumberland Line. 

&lt;p&gt;at this time, only two stations on the line have reached completion, Seaton Delaval (SEJ) and Ashington (ASL), with the rest planning to open 2025. the line operates from Newcastle, via Manors to the new stations, and is run with BR class 156s and BR class 158s. the service is half hourly, except sundays which is hourly. the intention is to run two car services. on the sunday i went all services i saw were four car. looking at Realtime Trains, this seems to have been the case the whole day, but since then only two car services have run. this makes some sense considering the increased ridership for opening day.

&lt;p&gt;this rail line also has integration with the Pop card. with my Pop Blue card each single was £1 and the daily cap was £2.20 across the whole network. it would be nice to see this integration for the rest of the rail lines in the area, and hopefully GBR will bring some of this. notably, the conductor on my service said they did not yet have a way to check you had tapped in with the Pop card.

&lt;p&gt;the stations are very minimal, mostly what you would expect for a small branch line. notably besides the posters, there is no Northern branding on any signs and such, similar to newly refurbished stations elsewhere on the network, like Morley in West Yorkshire. this seems to be preparation for trains running under GBR branding in the hopefully near future. they all have the standard itso reader for Northern stations, that is able to read the Pop card. 
</description>
        <link>/train/northumberlandline</link>
        <pubDate>17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>cardiff platform zero complete!</title>
        <description>2024-07-17

&lt;p&gt;Cardiff is a difficult one, because it's consistently out the way of me. however, with a lot of ticket splitting (8 tickets in total) i set off to VIC on an SE service, changed to PAD (making sure to go a convoluted route so i get to use the purple trains) and get a GWR service to GCR. here, i planned to change to a XC service the rest of the way to CDF, but typical of XC, it was cancelled. thankfully a kind GWR guard let me use my XC ticket on their service, and i made it to CDF. from there, i got a TfW service to PYE from the platform.

&lt;p&gt;the platform zero at CDF serves early morning XC services and TfW (AW) services to EBB.
</description>
        <link>/projects/plat0</link>
        <pubDate>18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>hot chocolate tierlist now has a page</title>
        <description>i've been ranking hot chocolates for a while and am making a tierlist of them. now it's on my website</description>
        <link>/projects/hot-choc</link>
        <pubDate>18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>i have an rss feed now?</title>
        <description>i have an rss feed now, i'll probably do something with it at some point</description>
        <link>/meta</link>
        <pubDate>18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 BST</pubDate>
    </item>
    
</channel>
</rss>
